《星际迷航4：抢救未来》
你怎么看？
What do you make of it?
好像是我们未知的文明 所发射的探测器
It appears to be a probe from an intelligence unknown to us.
继续用所有已知语言 传达 宇宙和平和你好
Transmit "peace" and "hello" in all known languages.
帮我接舰船总部 好了 船长
Get me Starfleet Command. Ready, Captain.
这是萨拉托加号星舰 正在第五中立区巡航中
This is U.S.S. Saratoga patrolling sector five, neutral zone.
我们正跟踪一个不明探测器 其轨道向着泰瑞太阳系
We're tracking a probe headed for the Terran solar system.
我们尝试与其联络 但在已知频率内没有回应
Attempts to communicate have been negative.
继续跟踪 萨拉多加号
Continue tracking,
我们将分析通讯信息并给你回复
we will advise.
明白 主舰 通话完毕
Roger, Starfleet.
六 五 四 三 二 一…
Six, five, four, three, two, one…
静止画面！停住！
Hold the image. Hold!
请看清这个货真价实的恶魔吧
Behold the quintessential devil in these matters:
詹姆斯 T.科克 叛徒 恐怖分子
James T. Kirk.
他不仅谋杀了一群克林根人 还偷走了他们的飞船
He murdered a Klingon crew and stole their vessel.
但真正的阴谋和意图
But here is the real plot.
正当联盟在此与我们进行和谈之时
While we negotiated peace,
科克正研制起源飞弹
Kirk was developing the Genesis torpedo.
这是科克的儿子构想出来的 并由他本人进行试爆
It was conceived by Kirk's son, and tested by the Admiral himself.
这可怕的能量所造就的 说得好听点 正是起源星球
This energy created what is called, euphemistically, the Genesis Planet.
其实是一个为灭绝克林根人而设的秘密基地
A base from which to launch the annihilation of the Klingon people.
我们要求引渡科克！我们要求得公道！
We demand the extradition of Kirk. We demand justice.
克林根人所谓的公正与众不同 总统阁下
Klingon justice is a unique point of view.
起源这个名字名副其实 生命的缔造者 而不是死亡
Genesis was perfectly named. The creation of life, not death.
克林根人首先引发了争斗 企图占有其中的秘密
The Klingons shed the first blood, attempting to possess its secrets.
你们凡根人是联盟里众所周知的智能玩偶
Vulcans are the intellectual puppets of this Federation.
你的战舰摧毁了格雷森号星舰 你的人杀死了科克的儿子
Klingons destroyed U.S.S. Grissom. Your men killed Kirk's son.
你否认这些事实吗？我承认
Do you deny these events? We deny nothing.
我们有权保护自己族人 你有权随意杀人么？
We must preserve our race. By committing murder?
肃静！
Silence!
不许再有扰乱秩序的事情发生
There will be no further outbursts from the floor.
总统先生 我来替被告说两句
I have come to speak on behalf of the accused.
纯属个人偏袒 科克救了他的儿子
Personal bias. His son was saved by Kirk.
大使先生
Mr. Ambassador,
我无意冒犯 不过委员会的商讨已经结束了
the Council's deliberations are over.
科克就这样逍遥法外？
Kirk goes unpunished?
科克船长被控违反了九项星舰条例
Admiral Kirk has been charged with violating Starfleet regulations.
星舰条例？太叫人不可容忍了！
Starfleet regulations? That's outrageous!
记住这一点：只要科克活着 就永无宁日！
Remember this well: There shall be no peace as long as Kirk lives.
船长日志 星际历 第8390天
Captain's log, stardate 8390.
这是流落到凡根星球上的第三个月
Three months of Vulcan exile.
麦考维博士以他独有的历史讥诮感
Dr. McCoy decided upon a name.
给夺取的克林根飞船重新命名
for our captured Klingon vessel.
我们和五百年前的叛变者一样 难以做出抉择
Like the mutineers of 500 years ago, we, too, have a hard choice to make.
马考伊博士 是 长官
Dr. McCoy? Aye, sir.
科蒂先生 是 长官
Mr. Scott? Aye, sir.
乌乎拉 是 长官
Uhura? Aye, sir.
查科夫 是 长官
Chekov? Aye, sir.
苏鲁 是 长官
Sulu? Aye, sir.
情况显示 前企业号的船长和船员
The commander and the crew of the late Starship Enterprise.
一致同意返回地球
have voted to return to Earth,
去面对营救史巴克船长所带来的严重后果
to face the consequences of their actions in the rescue of Capt. Spock.
谢谢各位 请回修理站去吧
Thank you all. Repair stations, please.
斯科蒂先生 我们什么时候能离开这里？
Mr. Scott, how soon can we be underway?
给我一天时间 要修复损坏部分不难
One more day. Damage control is easy.
要读懂克林根文可不简单
Reading Klingon is hard.
曾经希望他们至少派艘船来 虽然要接受军事审判有够糟的
It's bad enough to be court-martialed,
但是要乘这艘破克林根飞船回去…
but to have to go home in this Klingon flea trap…
我们可以从中学到不少 这艘船里还有隐形装置呢
This flea trap has a cloaking device that cost us a lot.
我只希望这船上的恶臭能消于无形
I just wish we could cloak the stench.
电脑 重新开始测试
Computer, resume testing.
是谁说：逻辑乃是我们文明的基石
Who said, "Logic is the cement of our civilization with.
因为有它我们才脱离了混沌状态
which we ascend from chaos"?
提普拉哈斯 我们凡根哲学的守护神
T'plana-Hath, matron of Vulcan philosophy.
铝亚硫酸盐结晶的分子式是什么？
What is the molecular formula of aluminum sulphite crystal?
后吃王 车吃王 兵吃车 将死
Queen takes knight, rook takes queen, pawn takes rook. Checkmate.
正确 克伦斯对生物工程所做出的贡献是什么？
Correct.What contribution to bioengineering was made on Klendth?
宇宙大气元素补偿物
The universal atmospheric compensator.
星舰传感器表明
Starship sensors indicate.
它曾被近距离追击
it is being pursued so closely, it occupies the pursuer's space.
识别对象及其文化特征 克林根干尸化浮雕
Identify object. Klingon mummification glyph.
1987年地球上发生了什么历史大事？
What historic event took place on Earth in 1987?
克林金沙第一定律是什么？虚幻的东西不存在
What is Kiri-Kin-Tha's first law? Nothing unreal exists.
调整此核磁成像中的正弦波 使反中性子得以通过
Adjust this sine wave so that antineutrons can pass through it.
钆是什么？
What is Gadolinium?
你感觉如何？
How do you feel?
我不明白这个问题 怎么了 史巴克？
I do not understand the question. What is it, Spock?
我不明白 母亲 你是半人类啊
I do not understand, Mother. You're half human.
计算机知道啊 这个问题毫无头绪
The computer knows that. The question is irrelevant.
史巴克 对你心智的重塑 用的是凡根人的方法
The retraining of your mind has been in the Vulcan way.
你可能不理解何谓感情
You may not understand feelings…
但作为我的儿子 你是有感情的
but as my son,
它们终将浮现
you have them.
希望如此 既然你认为它们有价值
As you wish, since you deem them of value.
但我不能在此干等 为什么？
But I cannot wait here to find them… Why?
你还有什么必须去的地方？
Where must you go?
我必须回地球去 去作证词
I must go to Earth, to offer testimony.
你这样做是为了友谊 我这样做是因为当时我也在场
You do this for friendship. I do it because I was there.
史巴克 众人的利益高于个人利益吗？
Spock… Does the good of the many outweigh the good of the one?
这是我所认知的公理
I would accept that as an axiom.
因为一个错误 你活生生地站在这里
Then you stand here alive because of a mistake.
一个由你的那些充满感情且并不完美的
made by your flawed, feeling,
人类朋友所犯下的错误
human friends.
他们牺牲了自己的未来 因为他们相信
They have sacrificed their futures because they believed.
你一个人的利益 对他们来说更为重要
that the good of the one, you, was more important to them.
人类会做出不合逻辑的决定 确实这样
Humans make illogical decisions. They do indeed.
来了
Here it comes now.
是什么造成的？
What's causing that?
他们的召唤是由强大的超幅电波传送的 带有巨大的能量
A powerful amplification wave.
能不能隔分离出这电波？
Can we isolate the wave?
不能 他正攻击我们整个系统
No, it's impacting on our systems.
黄色警告 开启防护罩 减缓接近速度
Yellow alert. Shields up. Reduce closing speed.
推进器失控 开启紧急推进器
Thrusters have been neutralized. Emergency thrusters.
无响应 舰长
No response.
紧急照明
Emergency lights.
损坏报告？所有系统全部失效 我们只剩后备动力可用
Damage report? Systems down. Reserve power only.
星舰总部 这里是萨拉多加号 能听见我说话吗？
Starfleet Command, this is Saratoga. Can you hear me?
请回答
Come in, please.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
报告情况 司令 情况不妙 总统先生
Status report, Admiral. Not good, Mr. President.
探测器正朝我们来 它的电波毁掉了沿路的一切
The probe is heading for us, damaging everything in its path.
克林根人已损失了两艘舰船
The Klingons have lost two vessels.
两艘星际舰和三艘小型太空船 都已失去动力
Two starships and three smaller vessels have been neutralized.
失去动力？怎么会这样 还不清楚
Neutralized? How? We don't know.
给我接约克郡号
Get me the Yorktown.
紧急频道0130 红色警报
Emergency channel 0130. Code red.
我们和外星探测器的接触已过了三小时
Since contact with the alien probe,
所有恢复动力的措施都失败了
all attempts to regain power have failed.
它们所使用的能量形态
It's using forms of energy.
连我们最好的科学家也弄不明白
we do not understand.
你能保护我们吗？我们发射了一切所能发射的装备
Can you protect us? We're launching everything.
我们的轮机长正试图 安装一个太阳帆加速系统
We are trying to deploy a makeshift solar sail.
若能成功的话 希望它能产生 足够的能量使我们生存
to generate enough power to keep us alive.
各系统报告 通讯系统 通讯系统准备完毕 长官
Systems report. Communications systems all ready.
通讯系统操作人 一如往常地做好了准备
Communications officer, as ready as she'll ever be.
苏鲁先生 导航系统正常
Guidance has a functional interface.
船上电脑将和星际联邦记忆库连线
with the Federation memory bank.
武器系统和隐形装置在所有飞行模式下均可正常工作
Weapons systems and cloaking device are operational.
令人惊喜呢
I'm impressed.
我们是在敌船里 我可不想因被击落
We're in an enemy vessel.
而踏上自己的葬礼之路
I did not wish to be shot down.
主机舱 报告 斯科特先生
Engine room, report.
准备好了 我已将锂定序器改进完毕
We're ready. The dilithium sequencer is now a little less primitive.
我已经替换了克林根粮仓
And I've replaced the Klingon food packs.
里面的气味令我作呕 原来如此
They were giving me a sour stomach. Is that what it was?
准备起航 不想去地球的请离船吧
Prepare for departure. Everybody not going to Earth had better get off.
萨维克… 该说再见了 是的 船长
Saavik… this is goodbye. Yes, Admiral.
谢谢你
Thank you.
长官 我一直没有机会 告诉你 你儿子的事
Sir, I have not had the opportunity to tell you about your son.
大卫死得很英勇 他救了史巴克
David died most bravely. He saved Spock.
他救了我们所有人 我想你应该知道这些
He saved us all. I thought you should know.
你好 史巴克船长 祝你旅途一帆风顺
Good day, Capt. Spock. May your journey be free of incident.
也祝你平安 中尉
Live long and prosper, Lieutenant.
请求允许上船 船长 请求批准
Permission to come aboard, Admiral.
吉姆 史巴克 叫我吉姆 你还记得吗？
Jim, Spock. Don't you remember?
在你执行指挥工作的时候 叫你吉姆是不合适的
It would not be proper to refer to you as Jim while you're in command.
而且我要为我的穿着道歉 我的制服不知上哪去了
Also, I must apologize for my attire. I seem to have misplaced my uniform.
就位吧
Station.
你确定这样好吗？你什么意思？
Is this a good idea? What?
我是说他 回到他的岗位 像什么也没发生过
Him, back at his post like nothing happened.
他肯定会受影响 没可能操纵好所有推进器的
He's not exactly working on all thrusters.
他会好起来的 你确定？
It'll come back to him. Are you sure?
我就知道
That's what I thought.
苏鲁先生 带我们回家吧
Mr. Sulu, take us home.
推进器正常
Thrusters functional.
脉冲功率达到百分之二十五
One quarter impulse power.
太空站 这里是星舰指挥中心
Space dock, this is Starfleet.
所有飞船起飞 所有飞船起飞
Launch all vessels.
太空站出入口无法开放 所有应急系统全部失效
Space dock doors are inoperative. All systems are non-functional.
启用后备能源
Engage reserve power.
星舰 太空站紧急呼叫 我们已失去所有内部动力
Starfleet, this is space dock. We have lost all internal power.
据测算以现在的速度 我们将在1.6小时后到达地球
Estimating planet Earth, 1.6 hours at present speed.
保持航道 查科夫先生 观测到联盟的护航舰吗？
Continue on course. Any sign of Federation escort?
没有 长官 完全没有巡航中的联盟飞船
No, sir, and no Federation vessels on patrol.
那就怪了 乌乎拉 通讯频道有什么消息？
That's odd. Uhura, what's on the com channels?
很活跃 全是多相传输 互相重叠 一片混乱
Very active. Multi-phasic transmissions. Almost a gibberish.
我试试能不能整理出来
Let me see if I can sort it out.
嗨 忙吗？
Hi. Busy?
乌乎拉很忙 我只是在监控
Uhura is busy. I am monitoring.
我很高兴你的Katra 能回到你的
It sure is nice to have your Katra back in your head,
而不是我的脑中
and not mine.
我或许能承载你的思想
I may have carried your soul,
但肯定无法取代你
but I sure couldn't fill your shoes.
我的鞋？
My shoes?
算了
Forget it.
也许我们能讨论点哲学问题
Perhaps we could cover a little philosophical ground.
生命 死亡 生命 大自然事物的本质
Life, death, life. Things of that nature.
我在凡根星的时候并没时间 复习哲学这门学科
I've not yet reviewed the philosophical disciplines.
别这样 史巴克 是我 玛考伊在和你说话
Come on. You really have gone.
你可到过别人都没去过的地方啊
where no man has gone before.
告诉我那是什么感觉？
Tell me what it felt like.
在没有参照物的情况下我们无法讨论
We have no frame of reference.
你说笑话吧 笑话…就是有幽默感的故事
You're joking. A joke is a humorous story.
要讨论你对死亡的看法我就得去死？
I have to die to discuss your insights on death?
抱歉 博士 我收到了大量的求救信号
I'm receiving a number of distress calls.
我相信如此
I don't doubt it.
阿拉斯加首府朱诺上空 云层覆盖范围上升到95%
Juneau, Alaska. Clouds increasing to 95%.
东京 全部被云笼罩 只能使用后备动力
Tokyo, total cloud coverage.
列宁格勒已经全部停电
Leningrad has lost all electrical power.
云的覆盖范围达到100% 温度迅速下降
Cloud coverage 100%. Temperature decreasing rapidly.
地球云层总的覆盖范围是多少？
What is Earth's total cloud coverage? 78.6%.
向所有空站通告 星舰紧急情况
Starfleet emergency. Red alert.
紧急警报 迅速转用行星储备能源
Switch to planetary power reserves.
即使用上所有的行星储备能源
Even with all planetary reserves.
没有太阳我们还是不能生存
we cannot survive without the sun.
我清楚得很
I'm well aware of that.
沙瑞克大使 恐怕您和我们一块被困在这了
Ambassador Sarek, I'm afraid you're trapped here with us.
我们没法回应这个探测器
There's no way we can answer this probe.
如果对问题完全不了解 当然没法作出回应
It's difficult to answer when one does not understand the question.
你或许该发出一个行星求救信号…
Perhaps you should transmit a planetary distress signal…
…在我们还有时间的时候
…while we still have time.
司令官？怎么了？
Admiral? What is it?
多重的求救信号 还有一条来自联盟的信息
Overlapping distress calls and a message from the Federation.
播放出来
On screen.
我是星际联邦的总统
This is the President of the United Federation of Planets.
不要接近地球
Do not approach Earth.
一个轨道探测器发出的信号 正在摧毁地球的一切
The transmissions of an orbiting probe are critically damaging this planet.
它正在电离大气层 所有电源都瘫痪了
It is ionizing our atmosphere. All power sources have failed.
所有环地飞船电力不足 探测装置正在蒸发海洋
Earth-orbiting starships are powerless. The probe is vaporizing our oceans.
除非我们能找出与它沟通的方式 否则我们就将灭顶
We cannot survive unless a way can be found to respond to the probe.
进一步的通信已不可能了
Further communications may not be possible.
节省你的能源 保住你们自己
Save your energy. Save yourselves.
不惜一切代价远离地球 永别了
Avoid the planet Earth at all costs. Farewell.
能让我们听听探测器发出的信号么？
Let's hear the probe's transmission.
是 长官！已接到扬声器上
Yes, sir. On speakers.
史巴克 你怎么看？极不寻常
What do you make of that? Most unusual.
是具备高能量高智商的未知能量形式
An unknown form of energy of great power and intelligence,
完全察觉不出其传输信号是破坏性的
unaware that its transmissions are disruptive.
我觉得认为其敌对是不合逻辑的
I find it illogical that its intentions be hostile.
那你觉得它是在说 嗨你好啊 地球 吗？
You think this is its way of saying, "Hi, there!" to Earth?
地球上还有其他形式的生命 博士
Only human arrogance would assume.
只有自大的人类才会以为 它是针对人类的
the message must be meant for man.
你的意思是 这信号
You're suggesting the transmission is meant.
是给其他生命体 而不是人类的？
for a life form other than man?
至少有这可能性 船长
It is a possibility. The President did say it was directed at Earth's oceans.
总统的确说过 它对准的是地球上的海洋
The president did say it was directed at Earth's oceans.
你能否根据密度 温度和盐度
Can you modify the signals accounting for density,
来修改探测信号呢？
temperature and salinity.
我试下 长官
I can try, sir.
成功了
I think I have it.
这就是在水下听起来的声音？
This is what it would sound like underwater?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
令人着迷
Fascinating.
如果我没猜错的话 这条信息不会有回应的
If my suspicion is correct, there can be no response to this message.
你去哪？去证实我的理论
Where are you going? To test my theory.
布恩斯 你待在这儿 不行 我要盯着他
Bones, you stay here. No way, I want to keep an eye on him.
正如所料 这些传输信号是鲸的歌声
As suspected, the transmissions are the songs sung by whales.
鲸？确切地说 是驼背鲸
Whales? Specifically, humpback whales.
简直疯了 谁会从几百光年外
That's crazy.
发射个探测器来和鲸讲话？
Who would send a probe to talk to a whale?
很有可能 鲸鱼在地球上的出现远早于人类
Whales were on Earth far earlier than man.
在1000万年前 驼背鲸被人类大量捕杀
10 million years earlier. Humpbacks were heavily hunted.
21世纪的时候就灭绝了
They died out in the 21st century.
这个外星探测器很可能就是来探测
The alien probe could be here to determine.
它们为什么失去了联系的
why they lost contact.
这种驼背鲸的回应可以被模拟吗？
Could the humpback's answer to this call be simulated?
声音可以 语言不能 我们可以用混合的信息回应
The sounds, but not the language. We would be responding in gibberish.
这物种在别处可以找到吗？
Can the species be found elsewhere?
不行 驼背鲸只有地球上才有
Humpbacks were indigenous.
而且是往日的地球
to Earth.
那我们没得选择
Then we have no choice.
我们必须在它毁掉地球前 毁掉这个探测器
We must destroy the probe.
这样做是没用的
To attempt to do so would be futile.
我们总不能就这么掉头离去 总得有个选择吧
We can't just turn away. There must be an alternative.
有一种可能性 虽然我不能保证一定成功
There is one possibility.
我们可以试着去把驼背鲸找回来
We could attempt to find some whales.
你刚才还说哪都没有 只有地球上有过
You just said there aren't any, except on Earth of the past.
我正是那样说的
That is exactly what I said.
如果是这样… 等一下
Well, in that case… Wait just a damn minute.
史巴克 算一下时间翘曲度
Spock, start your computations for time warp.
布恩斯 跟我来
Bones, come with me.
我们需要那些能量来维持医疗设施运转
We need that power to keep medical facilities functioning.
所有地下储藏系统关闭
All underground storage systems have been shut down.
斯高蒂 这个海湾有多长？大约60英尺
How long is this bay? About 60 feet.
你能围住使水不外流吗？应该能吧 你想游泳啊？
Can you enclose it to hold water? Are you planning to take a swim?
为了脱离困境 我们必须得找些驼背的
Off the deep end. We've got to find some humpbacks.
驼背的人？鲸鱼 威尔士先生 鲸鱼
Humpbacked people? Whales.
45-50英尺长 每只大概40吨重
45-50 feet long, about 40 tons each.
你真想用这只生锈的破桶做时间旅行吗？我们之前做过
You're going to try time travel in this rust bucket?
首先得绕着太阳旋转
You'd have to slingshot around the sun to.
还没获得足够速度 你就先被烤熟了
pick up enough speed.
你宁可什么都不做？我更偏好常识
Would you prefer to do nothing? I prefer common sense.
你打算带我们回到过去 找到驼背鲸
We go back in time, find some whales,
把它们及时带回来
then bring them forward in time,
希望它们能让探测器消失 基本如此
and hope to hell they tell this probe to clear off?
真是疯狂！还有更好的主意吗？
That's crazy! You have a better idea?
计算进行中 乌乎拉 替我接通星舰司令官
Computation is in progress. Uhura, get me Starfleet Command.
我接受到一个微弱的信号 好像是科克船长发的
I'm picking up a faint transmission from Admiral Kirk.
播放到屏幕上
On screen.
星舰司令官 我是詹姆斯 科克船长
Starfleet Command, this is Admiral James T. Kirk.
我们已经截获并分析了探测器的呼叫
We have intercepted and analyzed the call of the probe.
使用卫星备用电源
Go to reserve power.
我们认为只有灭绝了的驼背鲸
It is our opinion that only the extinct humpback whale.
才能正确地回应探测器
can give a proper response to the probe.
稳住 用后备电源 星舰司令官
Stabilize.
听到我说的了吗？我们听见了 请继续
Emergency reserve.
我们要尝试时间旅行
We are going to attempt time travel.
我们正计算当下的时空隧道
We are computing our trajectory at this time.
接回来
Get him back!
准备连线电脑
Ready to engage computer.
我们的目的时间段是？20世纪晚期
What's our target in time? Late 20th century.
能再精确一些吗？
Can you be more specific?
用现有设备没法做到
I've had to programme.
我不得不把记忆中的变量进行编排
some of the variables from memory.
什么变量？燃料剩余量 舰体容积
What are the variables? Availability of fuel. Mass of the vessel.
以及驼背鲸的可能位置 这个时候 应该在太平洋盆地
Probable location of whales. In this case, the Pacific Basin.
你在脑子里运算这一切？是的
You programmed that from memory? I have.
天使和怪兽保卫我们 哈姆雷特 第一幕 场景四
"Angels and ministers defend us"."Hamlet", act 1, scene IV.
从不怀疑你的记忆力 打开电脑 准备翘曲飞行
No doubt about your memory. Prepare for warp speed.
防护罩 查科夫 防护罩启动
Shields, Mr. Chekov. Shields.
但愿傻人有傻福
May fortune favor the foolish.
开始翘曲飞行 苏鲁先生
Warp speed, Mr. Sulu.
翘曲空间2
Warp 2.
翘曲空间3 运行稳定
Warp 3. Steady as she goes.
翘曲空间4
Warp 4.
翘曲空间5
Warp 5.
翘曲空间6
Warp 6.
翘曲空间7
Warp 7.
翘曲空间8 热防护罩过载
Warp 8. Heat shields at maximum.
翘曲空间9！
Warp 9!
9.2，9.3… 我们必须达到开放速度
9.2, 9.3… We need breakaway speed.
9.5，9.6，9.7…
9.5, 9.6, 9.7…
9.8…
就趁现在！
Now!
我当初真不该离开他
I should never have left him.
吉姆 我们在哪？
Jim, where are we?
史巴克 你所说的那是世界的末日
You're talking about the end of everybody on Earth.
苏鲁先生…
Mr. Sulu…
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
是的 先生 我们情况怎么样？
Aye, sir. What is our condition?
损坏的推进器着火了 请显示图像
The breaking thrusters have fired. Picture, please.
地球… 但这是什么时候？史巴克？
Earth… But when? Spock?
从大气污染程度看 应该是20世纪后半叶
Judging by atmospheric pollution, the latter half of the 20th century.
干得不错 史巴克
Well done, Spock.
我们现在已经被地球此时的探测器发现了
We may be visible to them.
说得对 史巴克 启动隐形装置
Quite right. Engage cloaking device.
我们正穿过天际线进入黑夜 往北美西海岸一带追踪
Crossing the terminator into night. The west coast of North America.
我收到了鲸的歌声 用扩音器放出来
I am receiving whale song. Put them on speakers.
好奇怪
This is strange.
歌声是从旧金山传过来的
The song is coming directly from San Francisco.
从城市里来的？这不可能啊
From the city? That doesn't make sense.
船长 出了个大问题 你能下来一趟吗？
We have a serious problem.
时间旅行把这些克林根水晶耗尽了
It's these Klingon crystals. The time travel drained them.
这些晶体正在升华 分解 给我个准确的数字
They're decrystalizing. Give me a round figure.
我们能保持大概24小时的隐形状态
24 hours, staying cloaked.
之后我们就显形了 然后死在水里
After that we're visible and dead in the water.
我们没能量脱离地球引力的束缚 更不要说回家了
We haven't the power to break out of Earth's gravity or get home.
我不能相信事情会是这个结局
We can't stop now.
没有让它们再结晶的方法吗？
Can't we recrystalize the dilithium?
抱歉 船长 就算在23世纪也不可能做到
We can't even do that in the 23rd century.
船长 在20世纪或许可能
Admiral, there may be a 20th century possibility.
如果记忆不错的话 此时应该有核反应堆这类装置
I recall there was a dubious flirtation with nuclear fission reactors.
由于它们会导致毒副作用
They resulted in toxic side-effects.
熔断时代到来的时候就被取代了
and were replaced in the fusion era.
但这个时候 我们应该能找到一些
But at this time, we may be able to find some.
但你说它们有毒
But you said they were toxic.
我们可以制造一个能安全收集 那些高能量光子的装置
We collect only high-energy photons.
这些光子可以重新使锂结构结晶 理论上来说
These photons would recrystalize the dilithium structure… theoretically.
我们上哪能找到这些反应堆？
Where would we find these reactors?
核动力被广泛用在海军舰艇上
They were used in naval vessels.
旧金山 我出生在那儿
San Francisco. I was born there.
它看上去并没什么不同
It doesn't look all that different.
让我们在金门公园降落 遵命 先生 降落中
Set us down in Golden Gate Park. Aye, sir. Descending.
乌乎拉和查科夫安排处理 铀资源的问题
Uhura and Chekov are assigned the uranium problem.
马考伊博士 斯科特先生和苏鲁先生
Dr. McCoy, Mr. Scott and Mr. Sulu.
给我们转换一个装鲸鱼的容器
will convert us a whale tank.
哦 很有趣！
Oh, joy!
史巴克上尉和我会试着跟踪鲸鱼的歌声
while Spock and I attempt to trace these whale songs to their source.
我会为您准备好远距离通话用具 长官
I'll have bearing and distance, sir.
一定要非常小心 这是一个未知领域
Be very careful, this is terra incognita.
他们的很多习俗都会使我们惊讶
Many of their customs will take us by surprise.
很显然 这里没人见过天外来客
None of these people have ever seen an extraterrestrial.
这是一种极为原始而又偏激的文明
This is a primitive and paranoid culture.
查科夫 替每个小组 配备好移相器和通讯器
Take a phaser and a communicator.
除非有紧急情况 否则不要轻易联络
Radio silence except in emergencies.
身着制服者摘下等级勋章
Remove your rank insignia.
还有问题吗？好吧
Any questions? All right.
出发吧 各就各位
Let's do our job and get out of here.
我们的世界 还等待着我们去拯救…如果我们能做到
Our own world is waiting for us.
开始着陆程序 遵命 长官
Commence landing procedure. Aye, sir.
你们俩又打架了？我以为你们昨晚和好了
Were you two fighting again? I thought you made up.
你们俩为什么老是吵架？我喜欢她吵架时的样子
Why are you two always fighting? I like the way she fights.
我对她说你要是以为我会在个破烤炉上
I told her I wasn't spending $60.
花费60块钱 那你一准是疯了
on a damn toaster oven.
她有什么反应？
What did she say to that? Well…
究竟在搞什么鬼？！
What the hell was that?
你看见了吗？没有 你也没看见 闭嘴吧
Did you see that? No, and neither did you.
鲸鱼在哪里？283度 离这里15.2公里
Bearing to the whales? 283 degrees, 15.2 kilometers.
每个人都记住我们降落的位置
Everybody remember where we parked.
走路看着点 傻蛋！
Watch where you're going, dumb-ass!
你才是傻蛋！
Double dumb-ass on you!
这些人类能撑过20世纪真是个奇迹
It's a miracle our race survived.
他们仍在用钱 我们得弄点到手
They're still using money.
史巴克 其他人留下
Spock. The rest of you stay here.
你们分散点吧 免得看起来跟一群参观的学生似的
Break up, you look like a cadet review.
18世纪的美国人 很有价值
18th century American. Quite valuable.
你确定要当了它们吗？你给我多少钱？
You do want to part with them? How much will you give me?
这不是马考伊博士送的礼物吗？
Those were a gift from Dr. McCoy.
将来还会是的 美妙之处就在于此
And they will be again.
多少钱？如果镜片完好的话值得更多
How much? The lenses aren't intact.
我给你100 那算多吗？
I'll give you $100. Is that a lot?
就这么多了 别乱用
That's all there is. Don't splurge.
准备好了吗？开干吧
All set? Good hunting.
史巴克先生 我们走吧
Thanks to your restored memory,
多亏你恢复的记忆 再加上一点好运
and a little bit of good luck,
我们在旧金山闲逛就为了找一只驼背鲸
we're walking around San Francisco looking for humpback whales.
你怎么解决这个问题？简单的逻辑就能解释了
How will you solve this problem? Simple logic will suffice.
我们利用这张地图开始吧
I will make use of this map.
从乌乎拉那儿我得到了距离和方位
I have the distance and bearing from Uhura.
如果我们能找到与之相符的地点…
If we juxtapose our coordinates,
那么我们应该能找到那里 也就是在283.7度…
we should be able to find our destination 283.7 degrees…
我想我们会在索斯里托的鲸鱼馆
We'll find what we're looking for.
找到我们想要的
at the Cetacean Institute in Sausalito.
两只分别叫乔治和格雷西的驼背鲸
two humpback whales, George and Gracie.
你怎么知道的？简单逻辑
How do you know this? Simple logic.
零钱 是什么意思？
What does "exact change" mean?
我们该怎样转换出这个容器？
How do we convert this tank?
如果有透明铝… 那是好多年后才有的东西
If I had transparent aluminum… You're years too early for that.
我们得找找20世纪有否替代品 但上哪去找？
Let's find their equivalent. But where?
你找到了吗？是的 被美国政府拥有
Did you find it? Yes, now we need directions.
我们现在得了解去的方向
Now we need directions.
借问一下 你能告诉我阿拉米达 的海军基地怎么走吗？
Excuse me, can you direct me to the naval base in Alameda?
是存放核动力舰艇的地方
It's where they keep the nuclear vessels.
核动力舰艇
Nuclear vessels.
打扰一下… 我们在找核动力舰艇
Excuse us… We are looking for nuclear vessels.
你能告诉我 阿拉米达的海军基地在哪吗？
Can you tell me where the naval base is in Alameda?
你好 我们在找阿拉米达的核动力舰艇
Hello, we are looking for the nuclear vessels in Alameda.
你能帮助我们吗？阿拉米达海军基地在哪？
Can you help us? Where is the Alameda naval base?
核动力舰艇在哪？跨过海湾在阿拉米达
Where are the nuclear vessels? Across the bay in Alameda.
那就是我说的阿拉米达
That's what I said, Alameda.
不好意思
Excuse me.
对不起 你能把那噪音关掉吗？
Excuse me, would you mind stopping that noise?
不好意思 能关了那噪声吗？
Excuse me, would you mind stopping that damn noise?
船长 我能问你个问题吗？别叫我船长
Admiral, may I ask you a question? Don't call me Admiral.
你以前叫我吉姆 什么问题？
You used to call me Jim. What's your question?
我们到这里后 你说话的方式改变了
Your use of language has altered since our arrival.
夹杂着很多色彩浓重的隐喻
It is currently laced with more colorful metaphors.
你个超级大笨蛋 你是指脏话？
"Double dumb-ass on you." The profanity?
那是他们说话的方式
That's the way they talk.
没人会注意的 除非你用它们宣誓
Nobody pays any attention unless you swear.
看看这个时代的文学 比如呢？
Look at the literature of the period. For example?
杰奎琳 苏珊的作品 哈罗德·罗宾斯的小说
The works of Jacqueline Susann. The novels of Harold Robbins.
巨人
"The Giants".
下一个表演 鲸鱼的世界 五分钟后开始
The next showing of "The World of Whales" begins in five minutes.
我得走了
Here I go.
早上好
Good morning,
今早我是你们的导游
I'm your guide this morning.
我是吉莉安 泰勒博士 大家可以叫我吉莉安
I'm Dr. Gillian Taylor.
我是海洋鲸鱼研究院的副主管
I'm assistant director of.
请跟我来 如果听不到我的声音尽管开口
the Maritime Cetacean Institute.
鲸鱼研究院世界上唯一只展示 与鲸鱼有关的物品的馆所
The Cetacean Institute is the only museum devoted to whales.
如各位所见 我们提供很多东西
We have a great deal to offer,
相对于我们熟知的鲸鱼来说 那些东西就显得很小了
but that is small compared to what we don't know about whales.
有一个共同错误就是 误以为鲸鱼是鱼
One commonly held misconception is that whales are fish.
它们不是 和你我一样 它们是哺乳动物
They're not. They're mammals like you and me.
恒温动物 呼吸空气 哺乳喂养
Warm blooded, breathing air and producing milk to nurse their young.
鲸鱼会袭击人类吗？像里写的那样 不会
Do whales attack people? No.
大多数鲸鱼没有牙齿 它们有柔软 如口香糖般的结构
Most whales don't have teeth, they have a gum-like tissue.
可以捕食小虾 也限制了它们的攻击性
that strains tiny shrimp for food, and that is the limit of their hostility.
不幸的是 它们的天敌却极富攻击性
Unfortunately, their principal enemy is far more aggressive.
你指人类？说得委婉些
You mean man? To put it mildly.
有史以来 人类捕捉鲸鱼来做成各种制品
Men have always harvested whales for a variety of purposes,
而现在大部分的制品都可以合成了
most of which can be synthesized.
一百年前 人类用手掷鱼叉捕了很多鲸鱼
100 years ago, using hand-thrown harpoons, man did plenty of damage.
但是相比这个世纪 那都不算什么
But that is nothing compared to what he has achieved in this century.
人类捕杀鲸鱼已使其濒临绝种
Mankind has hunted whales to the brink of extinction.
世界上最大的动物蓝鲸 事实上已经灭绝了
Virtually gone is the blue whale, the largest creature on Earth.
尽管已尽力禁止捕杀 还是有国家和私商
Despite all attempts to ban whaling, there are still countries and pirates.
仍然参与到对这些无害生物的杀戮之中
currently engaged in the slaughter of these creatures.
驼背鲸的数量曾以几十万计 现在只有大约一万只存活
Humpback whales, once numerous, now number about 10, 000 specimens.
被捕杀的鲸鱼 还都未发育成熟
Those that are taken are no longer fully grown.
另外 很多雌鲸在怀孕期间被捕杀
In addition, many of the female whales are killed with their unborn calves.
捕猎一个种群致使其灭绝是不合理的
To hunt a species to extinction is not logical.
有谁说过人类存在是合理的？
Whoever said the human race was logical?
请跟我来 我将为你们介绍 机构引以为豪的成就
If you'll follow me, I'll introduce you to the institute's pride and joy.
这是世界上最大的天然海水池
This is the largest seawater tank in the world.
养着仅有的两头驼背鲸
It contains the only two humpback whales in captivity.
他们是成年驼背鲸 每只重达45000磅
They are mature humpbacks weighing 45, 000 pounds each.
它们在幼年时期游至旧金山海湾 然后被送到了这里
They wandered into San Francisco Bay as calves and were brought here.
我们叫它们乔治和格雷西
We call them George and Gracie.
太棒了 雌鲸和雄鲸在同一个池子里
It's perfect. A male and female in a tank.
我们可以把它们一起传回去 看来我们的运气不错
We can beam them up together.
很漂亮 不是吗？而且极其聪明
Beautiful, aren't they? And extremely intelligent.
请跟我来
If you'll follow me, please.
虽然它们教会我们很多东西
Despite all they're teaching us,
我们还是要把它们放回公海
we have to return them to the open sea.
首先 我们没有足够的钱
We simply don't have enough money.
来满足它们一天两吨虾的食粮
to feed them two tons of shrimp a day.
多久以后？很快
How soon? Soon.
这很糟糕 因为它们真的很友好
It's too bad, because they're really quite friendly.
我已经非常非常喜欢它们了
I've grown quite attached to them.
这是观看乔治和格雷西的 一种更好的方式 水下看
Now here's a much better way to see George and Gracie. Underwater.
你们听到的被称为鲸鱼之歌 雄鲸发出的声音
What you're hearing is recorded whale song, sung by the male.
它到处唱歌 唱6至30分钟
He'll sing anywhere from 6 to 30 minutes.
在海里 其它鲸鱼会接着把歌唱下去
In the ocean, other whales will pick up the song and pass it on.
这些歌每年都有变化 我们不知道其意义何在
The songs change every year. We don't know their purpose.
它们是导航的信号吗？
Are they a navigational signal?
它们是交配仪式的一部分吗？
Are they part of the mating ritual?
抑或是我们完全无法理解的交流方式？
Or is it pure communication beyond our comprehension?
坦率的说 我们并不知道
Frankly, we just don't know.
也许它在对那个人唱歌
Maybe he's singing to that man.
见鬼！容我失陪 请在此稍等
What the hell?! Excuse me, wait right here.
请让一下
Excuse me, please.
你在那干什么？跟她说吧
What were you doing in there? Yes, speak up.
尝试去和它们交流 交流 交流什么？
Attempting the hell to communicate.
你无权呆在这里！
You have no right to be here!
听到这位女士说什么了吗？
You heard the lady.
如果我们把这些鲸鱼看成自己的
If we assumed that these whales are ours to do with.
认为自己能对它们为所欲为
as we please,
我们将会和那些造成他们 濒临灭绝的人一样有罪
we would be as guilty as those who caused their extinction.
我不知道发生什么了
I don't know what's going on,
但是你们马上离开 否则我就报警了
but get out now, or I call the cops.
那没有必要 我们只是想帮忙
That's not necessary. We're trying to help.
你的朋友在骚扰我的鲸鱼
Your friend was messing up my whales.
他们喜欢你 但是它们不是你的
They like you, but they are not the hell your whales.
我想 是它们告诉你的吧 它们怎么可能
I suppose they told you that. The hell they did.
是啊
Right.
史巴克 关于那些我们讨论过的 色彩浓重的隐喻
Spock Yes? About those colorful metaphors that we discussed.
我想你没必要再用它们了
You haven't quite got the knack of it.
为何？首先 你还没完全掌握技巧
Why not? You haven't quite got the knack of it.
还有别老是说真话
I see. it's not always necessary to tell the truth.
我不能说谎 我不是指撒谎
I cannot tell a lie. I don't mean lie.
但你可以夸大其辞 你以前这么干过
But you could exaggerate. You've done it before.
你不记得了吗？见鬼 我不记得了
Can't you remember? The hell I can't.
你从精神交流中还知道了什么？鲸鱼们不喜欢人类
What else did you learn? Their species is unhappy with man.
它们愿意帮助我们吗？我把我们的意图说得很清楚了
Are they going to help us? I communicated our intentions.
没事了 我明白 他们并不想伤害你们
It's all right. I know. They didn't mean any harm.
听说这里有些奇事 只是两个傻瓜
I heard there was some excitement. Just a couple of kooks.
你还好么？我很好
How are you doing? I'm fine.
别对我隐瞒了 我太了解你了
Don't tell me fish stories, I've known you too long.
鲍勃 别再让我为难了
Bob, it's tearing me apart.
我也这么觉得 但是我们深陷进退两难的境地
I feel the same, but we're stuck between a rock and a hard place.
无论是让它们留在这里 还是放归它们
If we keep them here or let them go,
还是会威胁到它们的生命
we're still risking their lives.
我知道
I know.
它们不是人类 它们的智商是…
They're not human beings. Their intelligence is…
够了 鲍勃 我对的同情心
My compassion is not limited to.
并不取决于其智商的高低
my estimation of one's intelligence.
队长 这里是第二小队 我已经有了反应堆的坐标
Team leader, this is team two. I have the co-ordinates of the reactor.
这里是科克 我们已经找到了核动力舰艇
Kirk here. We have found the nuclear vessel.
干得不错 船长 那是企业号
Well done. Admiral, it is the Enterprise.
明白了 你有什么计划？
Understood. What's your plan?
我们今晚进去收集光子 没人会知道
We will beam in tonight and collect the photons. No one will know.
明白同意 保持联系
Understood and approved.
通话结束
Kirk out.
她来了 如果我们能小心出牌
There she is. If we play our cards right,
应该能套出那些鲸鱼什么时候离开
we can find out about the whales.
打牌有什么用？这不是罗宾汉和他的随从吗？
How will playing cards help? It's Robin Hood and Friar Tuck.
你们要去哪？回旧金山
Where are you fellas heading? Back to San Francisco.
你们来就是为了游个泳？
You came all this way just for a swim?
我即使解释也无济于事 我同意
I won't try to explain. I'll buy that.
那他呢？他是好人
What about him? He's harmless.
在六十年代的话 他就是伯克利
Back in the 60s, he was part of.
言论自由运动的中坚力量
the free-speech movement at Berkeley.
他太有善心了（LDS美国慈善协会）
He did a little too much LDS. LDS?
我带你们一程
I'll give you a lift.
我总是 对不幸的人太过心软
I have a notorious weakness.
所以我才跟鲸鱼在一起
for hard-luck cases.
我们可不想惹麻烦 但你们已经那么做了 上车吧
We don't want to be any trouble. You've already been that. Come on.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
不要犯傻 那里有个拆轮胎棒 我伸手就能拿到
Don't try anything. I've got a tire iron right where I can get at it.
你们是伯克利人？我不是
So, you were at Berkeley? I was not.
他记忆也有问题 你们哪里人？
Memory problems, too. Where are you from?
爱荷华州 哦 怪不得不会游泳
Iowa. A landlubber.
你们俩在那里究竟想干什么？
What the hell were you guys really trying to do back there?
是不是为了男人之间的事？我很讨厌男人之间那点破事
Was it some kind of macho thing? I really hate that macho stuff.
我能问你个问题吗？说吧
Can I ask you a question? Go ahead.
你放了鲸鱼后会发生什么事情？
What's going to happen when you release the whales?
它们就得靠自己了 具体点？
They'll have to take their chances. What does that mean exactly?
像其他驼背鲸一样 他们将面临捕鲸者的危险
They'll be at risk from whale hunters just like all other humpbacks.
在研究院里你们说的灭绝 到底是什么意思？
What did you mean with all that stuff about extinction?
就是你给我们介绍时的意思 驼背鲸可能会灭绝
He meant what you said on the tour, that humpbacks may well disappear.
他用的时态可不是这样的 小子
That's not what he said, farmboy.
我们将会和那些造成他们
"We would be as guilty.
濒临灭绝的人一样有罪
as those who caused,
这句话用的过去将来时
" past tense, "their extinction."
我的记忆奇佳 对你的话我记得一清二楚
I have a photographic memory. I see words.
你确定这时候不该用 那些精彩的隐喻吗？
Are you sure it isn't time for a colorful metaphor?
你们不会是那些教鲸鱼找鱼雷 的傻瓜士兵吧？
Are you some dipshit army guy trying to teach whales to retrieve torpedoes?
我们不是 还好 否则我马上就让你们滚下车
No dipshit. Good, I'd have let you off here.
格瑞西怀孕了
Gracie is pregnant.
你究竟是谁？不要再耍我了 你怎么会知道？
Who are you? Don't jerk me around. How do you know that?
我们还不能告诉你 让我说完
We can't tell you that. Let me finish.
我们不是部队里的人 也无意去伤害鲸鱼
We're not in the military and we intend no harm to the whales.
我们或许能帮到你 用你完全无法想象的方式
We may be able to help you in ways you couldn't possibly imagine.
我相信 我敢打赌 很有希望
Or believe, I'll bet. Very likely.
你还没完全听懂我们的意思 那是肯定的
You're not catching us at our best. That much is certain.
我想等晚饭的时候 我们再愉快地商量一下
I think we'd all be a lot happier discussing this over dinner.
你说呢？
What do you say?
你们喜欢意大利菜吗？
Do you guys like Italian?
不 喜欢
No. Yes.
我喜欢意大利菜 你也一样
Yes, I love Italian… and so do you.
斯科特博士 我是尼克斯博士 工厂经理
Professor Scott, I'm Dr. Nichols, plant manager.
非常抱歉 完全是个误会
I'm terribly sorry. There's been an awful mix-up.
我根本不知道你要来
I was never told about your visit.
我试着向他们解释来着
I tried to clear things up.
斯科蒂教授 我说你从爱丁堡来 一路奔波
I explained that you'd come from Edinburgh.
为的是研究普勒希公司的制作方法
to study Plexicorp's manufacturing,
可他们好像对此一无所知
but they don't know anything about it.
一无所知？
Don't know anything about it?
难以置信 我可是跑了几百万英里 几千 几千
I've come millions of miles. Thousands!
对 几千英里 应邀来检查 我强烈要求见你们的老板
I was invited on an inspection. I demand to see the owners.
斯科蒂教授 放松些
Dr. Nichols has offered to.
尼克斯博士会亲自带我们参观车间的
take us around the plant personally.
他答应了？是的 很荣幸
He has? With pleasure.
那可就不一样了 格里高利
That's different. Gregory.
我的助手可以参加吗 当然
May my assistant join us? Of course.
对你的角色可别太投入了
Don't bury yourself in the part.
你好 挺好看的机子 休伊204型的 对吧
Hi. A good-looking ship. Huey 204, isn't it?
没错 你也开飞机吗 嗯 到处去
Right on, do you fly? Here and there.
我上学那会儿驾驶过跟这个差不多的
I flew something similar in my Academy days.
那这个就不算什么新鲜玩意儿了 嗯
Then this must be old stuff to you. Yes…
不过挺有趣的 问你几个问题行吗 问吧
But interesting. Can I ask you a few questions?
你这地方不错 尼克斯博士
This is a fine place you have here.
谢谢 您的工程学知识让人叹服
Thank you. Your knowledge of engineering is most impressive.
在我们那儿 我们称他为神奇师傅
Back home we call him the miracle worker.
我给你们拿点喝的？尼克斯博士
May I offer you something?
我倒是有东西要给你
May I offer something to you?
什么 你还在从事聚合体的生产吧
Yes? You're still working with polymers.
还在？那我还能有别的可以干吗
What else would I be working with?
的确 有什么别的呢
What else indeed?
我换个方式说吧 60x10英尺
How thick would a piece of.
载水量18000立方英尺
your plexiglas need to be,
这样的树脂玻璃一般厚度是多少
at 60 feet by 10 feet to withstand pressure of 18, 000 cubic feet of water?
这个简单 六英寸 仓库里就有 我注意到了
Six inches. We have it in stock. I've noticed.
假设 只是假设 我有一个办法
Now, suppose…
可以让你制造出同样功能的玻璃
…I were to show you a way to manufacture a wall.
不过只有一英寸厚
that would do the same job, but be only one inch thick.
对你来说是不是有些价值 你开玩笑的吧
Would that be worth something? You're joking.
也许教授可以使用你的计算机
Perhaps the professor could use your computer.
请吧
Computer…
计算机… 计算机
Computer!
你好 计算机 用键盘就好
Hello, computer. Just use the keyboard.
键盘 多离奇
A keyboard, how quaint!
透明铝材 这就是通行证 孩子
Transparent aluminum? That's the ticket, laddie.
要花上好些年才能弄清这个模型的变化
It would take years to figure out the dynamics of this matrix.
是的 不过你会富有得难以想像
Yes, but you would be rich beyond the dreams of avarice.
是不是有些价值 要不我按删除？
So, is it worth something to you, or should I punch up "clear"?
别
No.
现在没空 玛德琳
Not now, Madeline.
你到底要干吗
What exactly did you have in mind?
等一下
A moment alone, please.
你应该意识到如果我们把方程式给他
Do you realize that if we give him the formula,
我们就会改变未来吧？
we're altering the future?
怎么啦？说不定就是他发明的呢
Why? How do we know he didn't invent the thing?
是哦
Yeah.
你肯定你不会改变主意？
Won't you change your mind?
我现在的脑袋有什么问题吗
What is wrong with the one I have?
开玩笑的 再见 老朋友 等等
A little joke. Goodbye, old friend. Wait a minute.
你怎么知道格雷西怀孕了 没人知道的
Nobody knows that Gracie is pregnant.
格雷西自己知道啊 我就在这儿等着
Gracie does. I'll be right here.
我们吃饭的时候他就在树丛里瞎逛吗
Is he just going to hang around the bushes while we eat?
他有他自己的方式
It's his way.
你信任我吗 绝对信任
Do you trust me? Implicitly.
大蘑菇和意大利辣香肠 多加些洋葱 再来一份羊腿片
Large mushroom and pepperoni, with extra onions and a Michelob.
选得好 你呢 先生 一样双份
Great choice. And you, sir? Make that two.
你这么可爱的女孩子 怎么会当上鲸鱼学家的
How does a nice girl like you get to be a cetacean biologist?
走运吧 失去这些鲸鱼你很沮丧
Just lucky, I guess. You're upset about losing the whales.
你很有洞察力
You're very perceptive.
怎样把鲸鱼送走呢
How will that be done, exactly?
用一架特殊的747把它们运到阿拉斯加
They'll be flown to Alaska.
在那里把它们放归大海 航空运输
They'll be released there.
然后你就再见不到它们了
That's the last you'll see of them?
是
See, yes.
不过我们在它们身上加识别装置
But we'll tag them.
再用特殊频率的无线电追踪它们
with special transmitters and monitor them.
我可以把这些鲸鱼带到别处去
I could take those whales somewhere…
到它们再也不会被猎杀的地方
…where they'd never be hunted.
从索斯里托出发 如果没有汽车
You can't even get from Sausalito to San Francisco.
你自己连旧金山都到不了
without a lift.
如果你对我的能力评价这么低
If I'm so inept,
我们还在这儿共进晚餐干嘛
how come we're having dinner?
为不走运的笨蛋 干杯
I'm a sucker for hard-luck cases. Cheers.
还有 你为啥和那个傻家伙一起旅行
Besides, I want to know why you travel around with that ditzy guy.
他知道格雷西怀孕了 还管你叫船长
who knows that Gracie is pregnant and calls you "Admiral".
你能把我的鲸鱼带到哪里去
Where could you take them… my whales?
它们在哪里才会安全呢 这个不是「何地」
Where would they be safe? It's not a matter of where,
而是「何时」的问题
but when.
就是现在 为什么
It would have to be right now. Why?
圈养的驼背鲸所产的幼鲸都活不了
No humpback born in captivity has ever survived.
问题是在海上它们也安全不到哪里去
But they won't be safe at sea because of.
现在刚好是捕鲸季节
all the hunting this time of year.
所以你都看到了 就像他们说的那样
So you see, that, as they say, is that.
见鬼
Damn.
那是什么 你有个寻呼机
What is that? You have a pocket pager.
你是医生吗
Are you a doctor?
发生什么了 我告诉过你不要打过来
I told you not to call me.
对不起 我以为你应该想知道
Sorry, I thought you'd like to know.
我们正要把它们带过来 好的 祝你们走运
We're beaming them in now. All right. Good luck. Kirk out.
原原本本告诉我吧 干嘛不告诉我鲸鱼什么时候走
You want to try it from the top? Tell me when the whales are leaving.
你是谁 你觉得我是谁
Who are you? Who do you think I am?
你不会是外太空来的吧
Don't tell me! You're from outer space.
不 我来自爱荷华 我只是在外太空工作
I'm from Iowa, I work in outer space.
那我就猜对了哦 我就知道迟早会有外太空来客的
I was close. I knew outer space was going to come into this.
要听事实吗 是的 我正听着呢
The truth? I am all ears.
好吧 告诉你事实
Okay… the truth.
我是23世纪末的人
I am from the late 23rd century.
我来的目的是
I've come back in time.
把两头驼背鲸带回去
to bring two humpback whales with me, in an attempt to…
让这个物种重新繁衍
…repopulate the species.
你为什么不直说呢 干嘛要在这里施展魅力
Why didn't you say so? Why all the coy disguises?
你想听细节吗 我无论如何不想错过
You want the details? Oh, I wouldn't miss this.
这些鲸鱼什么时候放归呢 好吧 到底…
When are the whales being released? Okay, what the hell.
你的朋友说对了 格雷西是怀孕了 而且就快生了
Your friend was right. Gracie is pregnant, very pregnant.
明天中午 在一个中等规模的表演场
At noon tomorrow, in a media circus,
这些鲸鱼会被船运出去
the whales get shipped out.
明天中午 我们要走了吗
Noon tomorrow? Are we leaving?
走吧 我们的时间不多了 那个可以打包吗
We don't have much time. Could we have that to go?
没问题 谁买单呢 在你那个时代不会没有货币吧
Sure. Who gets the bad news? They don't use money in your time?
我们确实没有
Well, we don't.
要多久 取决于我们与反应堆之间的屏蔽墙厚度
How long? It depends on the shielding.
船长 这是我吃过的最短一餐了
Well, Admiral, that was the briefest dinner I've ever had,
也是我听到过的最长的鱼故事
and certainly the biggest fish story I've ever heard.
告诉我鲸鱼身上发射器的频率是多少
Tell me something. The whale's transmitter, what's the frequency?
对不起 那是机密 瞧 我根本不知道你是谁
Sorry, that's classified. Look, I don't have a clue who you are.
你不会想带我参观你的飞船吧
You wouldn't want to show me around your spaceship, would you?
那并非我的第一选择 那好吧 我们到了
That wouldn't be my first choice. Well, there we are.
我到这儿来 就是要两头驼背鲸回到23世纪去
I am here to bring two humpbacks into the 23rd century.
要是没有别的选择
I can go to the open sea to get them.
我会到海里去抓 不过我还是想要你的那些
I'd rather have yours.
对我 对你 对它们都好
It's better for me. It's better for you. It's better for them.
想想吧
Think about it.
你到底是谁 自己想想
Who are you? Think about it.
可别想太久 我没时间了
Don't take too long. I'm out of time.
你要是改主意了 就到这儿找我 这儿？
This is where I'll be. Here?
就这公园里？对
In the park. Right.
明天早上容器就造好了 那就差不多了
The tank will be finished by morning. That's cutting it close.
第二组怎么样了 不知道 等他们打电话过来
What about team two? We're waiting for them to call.
见鬼 我们算走运的了 两头鲸鱼就在我们手里
Damn! We've been so lucky. Two perfect whales right here.
要是不赶快行动 我们会失去它们的
Now we might lose them.
那我们的任务很可能完不成了
Then our mission would fail.
任务？你说的是地球末日啊
Our mission? You're talking about the end of every life on Earth.
你有一半人类血统 你对这个没感觉吗
You're half human. Haven't you got any feelings about that?
又来了 太怪了 长官
There it is again. That's too weird. Commander.
你们不是在运行测试程序吗
Aren't you running the test program?
是的 不过显然能量正在枯竭
We're getting a power drain.
应该来自船体内部
It must be coming from inside the ship.
罗杰森指挥官 是的 长官
Commander Rogerson. Yes, Chief,
我们也在追踪那个 是什么呢
we're tracking that, too. What is it?
斯科蒂 我们准备好传送出去了
Scotty, we're ready for beam-out.
斯科蒂 听见了吗
Scotty, can you hear me?
知道了
Confirmed. Roger that.
司令部指挥官吗？我是罗杰森指挥官
This is Commander Rogerson.
4号反应堆有入侵者
We have an intruder in number four M.M.R.
斯科蒂 听到了吗 几乎听不到
Scotty, do you read? Lass, I can hardly hear you.
传输动力已经跌至最低了 我只能把你们分两次传回来
Power is down to minimal. I'll bring you in one at a time.
拿好收集器 你先走吧
Take the collector. You go first.
准备行动
Stand by.
斯科蒂
Scotty.
在吗
Hello?
快来啊
Come in, please.
斯科蒂 还要多久
Scotty, how soon?
查科夫 快要中断了 请再发信号
Chekov, you're breaking up. Please signal again.
听见了吗 斯科蒂 现在时机正好
Can you hear me? Now would be a good time.
不许动
Freeze!
查科夫
Chekov!
我和他失去联系了
I've lost him.
行星联盟的星际舰队查科夫指挥官
Commander Pavel Chekov. Starfleet. United Federation of Planets.
好的 指挥官 你有什么要说的吗
Right, Commander, is there anything you want to tell us?
说什么 你是谁 在这做什么 还有这些是什么？
Like what? Who you are and what these are?
我叫查科夫 星际舰队的一名指挥官
I am Pavel Chekov, a commander in Starfleet.
编号 656-5827 D
Service number: 656-5827 D.
从头说起 什么从头说起
Let's take it from the top. The top of what?
姓名 我的姓名吗
Name? My name?
要是敢跟我玩花招 你就完了
Play games with me, and you're through.
我完了？那我可以走了吗
I am? May I go now?
你觉得呢 他是个俄国佬
What do you think? He's a Russkie.
他当然是个俄国佬
Of course he's a Russkie,
不过还是个痴呆 我们最好通知华盛顿方面
but he's a retard or something.
别动 好了 给我射线枪
Don't move. Okay, give us the ray gun.
我命令你们 趴在地板上 否则我就开枪了
If you don't lie on the floor, I will have to stun you.
来啊 开枪吧 很抱歉 不过…
Okay, stun me. I'm very sorry.
大概是因为辐射
It must be the radiation.
让开
Gangway!
上甲板
Hit the deck!
那人摔下去了 派个医护兵过来
Man down. Get a corpsman over here.
有消息吗 没有 我不该把他留在那儿
Any luck? Nothing. I shouldn't have left him.
你做了你该做的 加油吧 会找到他的
You did what was necessary. Keep trying, you'll find him.
斯科蒂 你答应要对水晶做个评估的
Scotty, you promised an estimate on the crystals.
进展颇为缓慢 长官 明天能好
It'll be well into tomorrow.
还不够好 你应该做得更好才行
You've got to do better.
我会努力的 他可是有点焦躁啊
I'll try, sir. He's in a wee bit of a snit.
他是个感情深沉的人 还有别的新说法吗
He's a man of deep feelings. What's new?
它们昨晚走了 我们不想让大众和媒体发现
They left last night.
而且我觉得这样你更好受些
We thought it would be easier on you this way.
不让我说再见 就把它们送走了？你个混账！
You sent them away without even letting me say goodbye!
舰长 科克舰长
Admiral! Admiral Kirk!
科克舰长
Admiral Kirk!
科克舰长 听见我说话了吗
Admiral Kirk, can you hear me?
它们走了 我需要你帮忙 你在吗
They're gone. I need your help. Are you in there?
舰长 出了点事儿
Admiral, we have a problem.
科克舰长
Admiral Kirk!
科克舰长 听见我说话了吗
Admiral Kirk! Can you hear me?
天哪
Oh, my God!
你好 爱丽丝 欢迎漫游奇境
Hello, Alice. Welcome to wonderland.
这是真的 是真的
It's true! Yes, it is.
很高兴你能来 不过不是时候
I'm glad you're here, but you picked a hell of a time to drop in.
是真的吗 是的 看看吧
Is this real? Yes, take a look.
装你的鲸鱼的容器 可它们走了
Storage tanks for your whales. They're gone.
走了？昨晚就被带走了 也没告诉我
Gone? They were taken last night.
现在应该在阿拉斯加了 见鬼
They're in Alaska by now. Damn!
不过你可是去找它们的吧 我哪儿也去不了
But you can go find them, right? I can't go anywhere.
这算什么飞船啊 少了一个人的飞船
What kind of a spaceship is this? It's a spaceship with a missing man.
舰长 重获全部动力 谢谢 史巴克
Full power has been restored. Thank you, Mr. Spock.
你好 博士 欢迎登机
Doctor, welcome aboard.
舰长 您在吗 乌乎拉 出什么事啦
Admiral, are you there? Uhura, what's wrong?
我找到查科夫了 他们要带他去动个紧急手术
I've located Chekov. They're taking him to emergency surgery.
在哪儿 慈善医院
Where? Mercy Hospital.
在使馆区 他情况危殆
The Mission District. His condition is critical.
应该活不了了
He's not expected to survive.
让我去 别让他落在20世纪的医生手里
Let me go in there. Don't leave him in the hands of 20th-century medicine.
我觉得麦考伊博士是对的 我们应该帮助查科夫
I suggest that Dr. McCoy is correct. We must help Chekov.
这样做合逻辑吗 不合逻辑 但符合人性
Is that the logical thing to do? No, but it is the human thing to do.
好吧 你能帮我们吗
Right. Will you help us?
怎么帮 我们看上去要像医生
How? We'll have to look like physicians.
我们试试这里 你检查那里
We'll try down here. You check there.
什么情况？肾透析
What's the matter? Kidney dialysis.
透析 这是什么 黑暗时代吗
Dialysis? What is this, the Dark Ages?
给 吞下去 要是还有问题 找我
Here, swallow that. If you have any problems, call me.
找到了
Here, I've got it.
走吧
Let's go.
他关在警戒区 再上一楼
He's being held in the security corridor one flight up.
情况危殆
His condition is critical.
打扰了 我们来
Excuse me, we'll take that.
顶住门 紧急情况
Hold the door. Emergency.
我就在那儿 全都听见了
I was there. I heard the whole thing.
韦恩特拉伯说要彻底化疗
Weintraub said radical chemotherapy.
那哥特里伯呢 他说用图像疗法
What about Gottlieb?
我以为他们就要打起来呢
He talked about image therapy.
难以置信 你有不同意见吗
Unbelievable! You have a different view?
听上去像西班牙的宗教审判所 糟糕的一天
It sounds like the Spanish inquisition. Bad day.
让让 对不起 我们有命在身
Out of the way. We have orders…
见鬼 你想让她死在你手上吗
Damn it! This is an acute case.
这女士是典型的上腹腔水肿
of upper-abdominal distension.
让开
Get out of the way!
你说她得了什么病 肚子痛
What did you say she's got? Cramps.
你们是谁 不戴口罩 这些人是谁
You aren't masked! Who are these people?
不认识 你在干嘛
I don't know. What are you doing?
切开脑动脉 你读的什么学位 牙科吗
Tearing of the meningeal artery. What's your degree in, dentistry?
你怎么解释脉搏低 呼吸缓慢和昏迷呢
How do you explain slow pulse, low respiratory rate and coma?
做个眼底检查 对于这个个案 眼底检查毫无用处
A funduscopic examination… …is unrevealing.
去除血肿就会降低脑压
An evacuation of the haematoma will relieve the pressure.
天啊 在他脑袋上钻个洞是不行的 应该修补动脉
Drilling holes in his head is not the answer. The artery must be repaired.
把你的屠刀拿开 让我来救他 要不就太迟了
Put away your butcher knives and let me save this patient.
我要让他们开除你 如此外行的行为
I'll have you removed. Such unprofessional behavior…
进那个小房间吧 那是什么 一把枪吗
Into that little room. What is that? A gun?
这是什么 不知道
What is this? I've no idea.
他把锁给熔化了
He melted the lock.
我们简直是在跟中世纪的人打交道
We're dealing with medievalism here.
化疗 还有眼底检查
Chemotherapy! Funduscopic examinations!
查科夫 醒醒
Chekov, wake up.
查科夫 听见我说话了吗
Pavel, can you hear me?
他要醒过来了 查科夫 跟我说话呀
He's coming around. Pavel, talk to me.
姓名 职务
Name? Rank?
姓名：查科夫
Chekov, Pavel.
职务：指挥官
Rank: Admiral.
病人怎么样了 他会没事的
How's the patient? He's going to make it.
你是和一女病人一起进去的呀 小小的失误
You came in with a she. One little mistake.
让我们出去
Get us out of here.
他们带走了病人 找人帮忙
They've taken the patient.
停下
Hold it!
现在不行 查科夫 停下
Not now, Pavel. Hold it.
那个医生给了我一粒药片 我就长出了一个新的肾脏
The doctor gave me a pill and I grew a new kidney.
而且功能完好
It's fully functional!
不许动
Freeze.
现在鲸鱼会在哪儿呢 给我海图 我会指给你看的
Where would the whales be by now? Do you have a chart?
不 我只需要无线电频率去追踪它们
Just give me the radio frequency.
你说什么呢 我要跟你一起去
What? I'm coming with you.
不行的 我们的下一站是23世纪
Our next stop is the 23rd century.
我不在乎 我反正也是孤身一人
So, I've got nobody here.
我要帮那些鲸鱼 我没时间跟你争论了
I've got to help those whales. I've got no time to argue.
给我无线电频率 401兆赫
The radio frequency, please. 401 megahertz.
谢谢…你所做的一切
Thank you… for everything.
斯科蒂 把我运回去
Scotty, beam me up.
惊喜
Surprise.
史巴克 动力到底在哪儿 再等一分钟 舰长
Spock, where the hell's the power? One damn minute, Admiral.
我在回忆这个的工作原理 我得习惯用休伊（飞机）
I'm trying to remember how this worked. I got used to a Huey.
你耍我 你需要我
You tricked me. You need me.
坐吧 苏鲁先生
Take a seat. Now, Mr. Sulu.
那是什么鬼东西
What was that?
隐形装置稳定 系统正常
Cloaking device is stable. All systems normal.
继续助推攀爬 机翼 5x0 舵 稳定
Maintaining impulse climb. Wing: Five by zero. Helm: Steady.
建议 推进到10000 转舵 310
Advise reaching 10, 000. Steer 310.
乌乎拉 搜寻鲸鱼 401兆赫 正在搜寻
Uhura, scan for the whales. 401 megahertz.
推进到10000了 舰长
10, 000, Admiral.
机翼 巡航模式 全速前进
Full impulse power.
转舵310 到白令海峡 预计时间 12分钟
310 to the Bering Sea. ETA: 12 minutes.
鲸鱼容器安全吗 当然 但我从没运输过400吨东西
Are the whale tanks secure? Aye, but we're beaming up 400 tons.
400吨？不止是鲸鱼 还有水
It's not just the whales, it's the water.
当然了
Yes, of course.
有信号吗 没有
Any contact? Negative.
你好像有问题 你的感觉完全正确
You appear to have a problem. Your perception is correct.
要回到23世纪我们出发时的准确时段
In order to return us to the exact moment.
我以回溯的时间之旅作为参照物
we left the 23rd century.
计算了加速度曲线的相关用时
I calculated the time elapsed in relation to the acceleration curve.
这个应该的 问题何在呢
Naturally. So what's your problem?
加速度不再是恒定值 那就尽力吧
Acceleration is no longer a constant. Then take your best shot.
怎么尽力 猜啊 史巴克
Best shot? Guess, Spock.
尽力地猜想 猜可不符合我的个性
Your best guess. Guessing is not in my nature.
没有人是完美的
Well, nobody's perfect.
就是它了 联系上鲸鱼了
That's it! Affirmative. Contact with the whales.
方位：327 范围：600 海里
Bearing: 327. Range: 600 nautical.
放到屏幕上 你是怎么做的
Put it on the screen. How can you do that?
我在鲸鱼中测到了一个信号 方位 328度
I have a signal closing in on the whales, bearing 328 degrees.
看看吧
Let's see it.
那是什么船 捕鲸船 我们来晚了吗
What kind of ship is that? A whaling ship. Are we too late?
全速降落 是
Full-power descent. Aye, sir.
十秒钟 长官
Ten seconds, sir.
好的 看你的了 斯科蒂 十秒钟 舰长
All right, Scotty. Ten seconds, Admiral.
五 四 三
Five, four, three…
二 一
…two, one.
舰长 鲸鱼在这里
Admiral, there be whales here!
干得好 我们的翘曲速度呢 全速 长官
Well done. Do we have warp speed? Full power now, sir.
请你… 苏鲁先生 是 长官 翘曲飞行
If you will, Mr. Sulu. Aye, sir. Warp speed.
苏鲁先生 我要带客人去看看她的鲸鱼
Mr. Sulu, I'm going to take our guest to look at her whales.
这些数量不定的鲸鱼群
How does the variable mass of whales.
怎么才能切合我们的重新繁衍计划
fit into our re-entry program?
斯科蒂先生没有给我准确的数目啊
Mr. Scott cannot give me exact figures…
我来猜 猜
I will make a guess. A guess?
你啊 史巴克 那可真不寻常
You, Spock? That's extraordinary.
我觉得他不明白 不
I don't think he understands. No.
他的意思是你的猜测 比多数人的事实更可靠
He feels safer about your guesses than most people's facts.
你是说他在恭维我 是的
You're saying it is a compliment? It is.
那我一定要做出最好的猜测
Then I will make the best guess I can.
「他们说海是冷冰冰的 其实海里流淌着最热的血」
"They say the sea is cold, but the sea contains the hottest blood of all."
「鲸鱼不哭」 D.H.劳伦斯写的
"Whales Weep Not", D.H. Lawrence.
真够有讽刺意味的 人类杀死这些生物的时候
It's ironic. When man was killing these creatures,
正是在毁灭自己的未来
he was destroying his own future.
这些动物似乎见到你很高兴 博士
The beasties seem happy to see you.
希望你喜欢我们的鱼缸
I hope you like our aquarium.
一个奇迹 斯科蒂教授 奇迹 奇迹还未降临呢
A miracle, Mr. Scott. A miracle? That's yet to come.
什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是也许我们成功不了 你应该呆在你所属的地方
We might not make it. You should have stayed where you belong.
我属于这里啊 我是个鲸鱼学家
I belong here. I am a whale biologist.
假设真有奇迹 你能把它们运过去
Suppose by some miracle you do get them through?
23世纪除了我还有谁了解驼背鲸呢 说到点子上了
Who in the 23rd century knows anything about humpback whales?
舰长 你最好上来看看 我们的动力正在下降
Admiral, you'd better get up there. We're having a power fall off.
陪着它们 我来了
Stay with them. I'm on my way.
顶住
Hold on tight.
翘曲 7.5
Warp 7.5.
7.9 防护已是最大值了
7.9. Shields at maximum.
我能做的就这么多了
That's all I can give you.
我们能采用急剧坠速吗 无法确保
Can we make breakaway speed? I cannot guarantee it.
我改变轨道来抵消
I shall compensate by altering our trajectory.
翘曲8… 8.1 最大速度
Warp 8… 8.1. Maximum speed.
我需要推进器控制 推进器由史巴克控制
I need thruster control. Thrusters at Spock's command.
稳住 稳住 好了
Steady… Steady! Now!
加速器停止了 是的 舰长
Did breaking thrusters fire? They did, Admiral.
那我们到底在哪儿
Then where the hell are we?
探测器
The probe.
状况报告 史巴克 没有数据 舰长 计算机不能用
Condition report. Computers are non-functional.
主动力停了 备用动力没有回应
The mains are down. Aux. Power is not responding.
转为手动操纵 控制不了 长官
Switch to manual control. I have no control, sir.
我们在哪儿呢 完全失控 象蝙蝠一样两眼瞎
Where are we? Out of control and blind as a bat.
再接通他
Get him back.
看 他们朝着大桥前进
Look! They're heading for the bridge.
可以的话 请把鼻子抬高些
Keep the nose up if you can.
我们在水里了 打开舱口
We're in the water. Blow the hatch.
我们现在要做的就是让鲸鱼出去
Now all we have to do is get the whales out of here.
斯科蒂 听见了吗
Scotty, do you hear me?
走啊 走啊 注意所有人的安全 我会的
Move! See to the safety of all hands.
抓住我的胳膊 抓住了
Lassie, get my arm. I've got it.
舰长 帮个忙 我在这儿 斯科蒂
Admiral, help! I'm here, Scotty.
你会没事的 鲸鱼被困住了
You're going to be all right. The whales are trapped.
分隔舱门没有电了 炸药呢
There's no power to the bay door. Explosive override?
在水下没办法拿到啊
It's underwater. We can't reach it.
你上去 关上舱门
You go on ahead. Close the hatch.
你会被困住的 去啊
You'll be trapped. Go on!
看见它们了吗
Do you see them?
那儿
There!
它们干嘛不回应 不唱歌
Why don't they answer? Why don't they sing?
总统先生 我们又有动力了
Mr. President, we have power.
委员会议现在开始
The Council is now in session.
请坐
If you will all take your seats.
把被告带进来
Bring in the accused.
史巴克队长 你不必站着接受指控
Capt. Spock, you do not stand accused.
总统先生 我要和队友们站在一起
Mr. President, I stand with my shipmates.
好吧
As you wish.
罪名是…
The charges are…
共谋 袭击联盟官员
Conspiracy. Assault on Federation officers.
偷盗联盟财产 企业号飞船
Theft of Federation property, namely the Starship Enterprise.
破坏联盟飞船
Sabotage of the U.S.S. Excelsior.
毁坏联盟财产 尤其是企业号飞船
Destruction of Federation property, specifically the U.S.S. Enterprise.
还有违抗星际舰队长官的命令
And finally, disobeying direct orders of the Starfleet Commander.
科克船长 你有什么辩解
Admiral Kirk, how do you plead?
我代表全体船员认罪
On behalf of all of us, I'm authorized to plead guilty.
请输入
So entered.
由于有从轻发落的表现 所有指控只有一项成立
Because of mitigating circumstances, all charges but one are dismissed.
剩下的唯一指控：违抗上级长官的命令
The charge of disobeying orders of a superior officer.
只针对科克船长
is directed solely at Admiral Kirk.
相信船长意识到纪律的必要性了吧
I'm sure the Admiral will recognize the necessity for discipline?
是的 先生 詹姆斯.T.科克
I do, sir. James T. Kirk…
审判结果是 你由船长降级为队长
It is the judgment of this council that you be reduced in rank to captain.
由于该项判决 你将承担
As a consequence of your new rank,
你已经通过实践证实了 你有能力担当的职责
you will be given the duties for which you have demonstrated great ability.
指挥一艘飞船
The command of a starship.
请安静
Silence.
你和你的船员将这个星球 从短见中拯救了出来
You and your crew have saved this planet from its own short-sightedness.
我们永远欠你们的情
We are forever in your debt.
我为你感到高兴
I'm so happy for you.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
等等 你去哪儿 你有你的船 我有我的
Wait a minute, where are you going? You have your ship, I have mine.
科学号 我得学上300年
Science vessel. I've got 300 years of learning to do.
你是在说再见吗 为什么非得再见
You mean, this is goodbye? Why does it have to be goodbye?
就像你们那个世纪的人说的 我没有你的电话号码啊
Like they say in your century, I don't even have your phone number.
我怎么找你呢 别担心 我会回来找你的
How will I find you? Don't worry… I'll find you.
银河系见
See you around the galaxy.
爸爸
Father.
一小时内我就要回凡根星球了 我想向你道别一声
I am returning to Vulcan within the hour. I'd like to take my leave of you.
你为我这么费劲真是太好了 不费劲啊 你是我儿子
It was kind of you to make this effort. It was no effort. You are my son.
我对你在这次危机中的表现印象深刻
Besides, I am most impressed with your performance in this crisis.
谢谢
Most kind.
我记得我反对你在星际舰队服役
As I recall, I opposed your enlistment in Starfleet.
不过我的判断也有可能是错的
It is possible that judgment was incorrect.
你的同事都是好人
Your associates are people of good character.
他们都是我的朋友
They are my friends.
那是当然
Yes, of course.
要给你妈妈带个口信吗 是的
Any message for your mother? Yes.
告诉她…我感觉不错
Tell her… I feel fine.
长寿昌盛 爸爸 长寿昌盛 儿子
Live long and prosper, Father. Live long and prosper, my son.
这个宇宙中唯一永恒的是官僚政治
The bureaucratic mentality is the only constant in the universe.
我们会有艘货船 我还是希望是「求精号」
We'll get a freighter. I'm counting on "Excelsior".
你为什么还想要那几桶破螺钉
Why in God's name would you want that bucket of bolts?
船就是船 无论你说什么 先生 我们坚决执行
A ship is a ship. Whatever you say, sir. Thy will be done.
朋友们 我们回家啦
My friends… we've come home.
舵已就位 船长 好的 我们看看她能干些什么
Helm ready, Captain. All right, let's see what she's got.